hi this is Bonnie and I'm recording this
from the studio at all the Lauren site
Center one of the things I wanted to do
with these short videos is respond to
questions that some of you have given me
and really make it pertinent to what
you're thinking and what your concerns
are as young people facing your future
and so the daughter of a friend of mine
Kristina Bradley wrote in to me
yesterday and asked this question she
says what comes to me as I look into the
future is the question of how will I
listen deeply and stay true to myself
this has to do mostly with what career
path I choose to follow and what types
of people I choose to surround myself
with I am really trying to listen to
myself
and find where I am stuck and where I am
open and I hope to continue this
practice into the future as I look into
the future I see many new experiences
and opportunities and I wonder how
successful I will be listening to myself
and what I want out of life so this is
already a rich and genuine question and
there's a lot of gems in it but one of
the things that we can do is work on
making these types of questions more
generative and what I mean by that is
how can we work the question so that it
actually starts to answer or lean into
its own possibilities and if we were
actually in conversation this would be a
more generative conversation and I would
say something and there'd be some
feedback but we're working with these
digital snapshots where the int question
gets in one silo and then the answer
becomes an artifact so we're just going
to play with this question and see where
we can
and take it first of all you know but
it's very important to remember that a
life is unknown and only revealed
through the process of living it over
the entire lifetime so when you ask the
question stay true to myself be careful
that you're not making the mistake of
thinking that that's something static
that yourself is something formed or
fixed at any one point in time that has
to remain as it is and in fact life is a
generative unfolding of not only your
circumstances but what that core truly
is it it's it's latent in you it's still
a seed of wisdom let's say and you want
to be able to let life shape that as
you're shaping the circumstances of your
life so yes we want to have a sense of
being whole and congruent and authentic
but that sense of being whole and
congruent and authentic is a process of
opening to wider and wider possibilities
opening to new ways of being opening to
new friendships and sometimes moving
through old friendships going where the
enthusiasm takes us being able to
identify where our energy wants to go
and why it wants to go there to
understand that our purpose in life is
always shaping itself by our
relationships as I think you you wrote
but not only by our friendships and
oftentimes the most important or
significant relationships that we'll
have are people who never actually
become our friends they may be our
bosses then
maybe our co-workers they maybe people
that we spend time with in collective
situation but we never really got along
with and these are fabulous
opportunities to assimilate aspects of
the human condition but don't fit well
with you but if you allow that in and
you allow that to shape yourself and for
the wisdom to grow from that then your
life will be much more open and much
more rich so in this process then what
do we trust you know we talk about at
all the lower clarity of purpose or what
is clarity of purpose if it's not a
static thing so we associate clarity of
purpose with insight and intuition and
imagination so you use your intuition
which is an embodied sense a felt sense
that you you call it listening to
yourself which is a great phrase for it
to listen to yourself to listen to that
which is moving and that which is
stagnant and that which wants to move
and that which feels contained or
constrained and to keep opening that in
acknowledging that it's a process an
ongoing process it's something that is
alive and wants to change and wants to
grow and wants to generate and wants to
write them so this is the embodied
intuition enthusiasm and inspiration and
your imagination is a huge part of being
clear about your purpose because if you
don't imagine with enthusiasm or taking
an inspiration wherever it shows up and
allow that to shape your imagination of
who you can be or what you what is
possible then you're not going to be
able to feed sufficiently nurture that
energy that wants to open and blossom
and become more so the imagination
is a crucial partner to the intuition
insight and then the third aspect is the
insight itself and the insight is a
process of being able to lean into the
unknown so that you have this intuition
that you need to move that something
wants to move and you're doing an
insight process or insight practice of
using your imagination and and trying to
understand what is limiting in your way
of being that needs to be changed that
needs to open up and then you use the
insight practice to lean into the
unknown and stay open to the energy in
the enthusiasm without this knowing of
the final goal and so what happens is
you can use the energy the enthusiasm in
a practice of insight which will reveal
the next elegant step so that for
example I often know that what I'm doing
is really right but this decision I've
made to do this is really right but they
also know that it's not what I'm going
to be doing for a very long time and if
life is a process of generative
unfolding over a lifetime it's also a
nonlinear process so you can't get from
here to there in a straight line
it's very nonlinear and so you can be
sure that this step for now fits that
it's right for you but it's only a piece
of the puzzle a puzzle that will never
be known because it's always in an
unfolding process and so that's a little
way to work with your question and
opening it up to the possibilities that
it seeks so thank you for the question
and thank you for watching